<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Custer</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Custer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting a Basic R Markdown Website to Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/2019/07-convertwebsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/07-convertwebsite/</guid>
      <description>When I first discovered that it was possible to create a website using R Markdown’s built in site generator, I had not yet heard of blogdown. Using this great tutorial from Emily C. Zabor and the R Markdown: The Definitive Guide by Yihui Xie, J. J. Allaire, and Garrett Grolemund, I set out on a seemingly ambitious effort to create my own personal website; this is something that I would never have envisioned myself doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudoku Solver</title>
      <link>/sudoku/sudoku_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sudoku/sudoku_home/</guid>
      <description>This is long term pet project of mine. The ultimate goal of the project is to create an R Shiny app which will take an user provided image of a sudoku puzzle, read the data from the image, solve the puzzle, and return the results. The project will be broken into its major component parts. In general, the purpose of the project is to showcase some of my practical R experience, as well as to learn how to do several new things with R along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Test</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06-newdeparment1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06-newdeparment1/</guid>
      <description>I want to test this as a post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please feel free to reach out to me at: jamescuster0121@gmail.com
Or connect with me on GitHub,  Twitter,  Linkedin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday</title>
      <link>/tt/2019_01_29_dairycows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tt/2019_01_29_dairycows/</guid>
      <description>Dairy CowsData for Tidy Tuesday this week comes from the United States Department of Agriculture. The data and code books can be found here. There are five different data sets provided, and I will only look at the milk products facts data set which tracks Americans annual consumption of various milk products.
library(tidyverse)library(cowplot)library(viridis)theme_set(theme_light())MilkProductFacts &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/master/data/2019/2019-01-29/milk_products_facts.csv&amp;quot;)MilkProductFactsTidy &amp;lt;- MilkProductFacts %&amp;gt;% gather(product, lbsPerPerson, -year) %&amp;gt;%mutate(product = str_to_title(str_replace_all(product, &amp;quot;_&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; &amp;quot;)))MilkProductFactsTidy %&amp;gt;% ggplot(aes(year, lbsPerPerson, color = product)) +geom_line(size = 1) +scale_colour_viridis_d() + labs(x = &amp;quot;Year&amp;quot;,y = &amp;quot;Pounds consumed per person&amp;quot;,title = &amp;quot;Average US Milk Product Consumption 1975-2017&amp;quot;,color = &amp;quot;Products&amp;quot;) +theme(legend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday</title>
      <link>/tt/tthome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tt/tthome/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday is a weekly event put on by the R for Data Science online learning community. Each week they release one or more data sets to give individuals the opportunity to practice data wrangling and visualization skills. This is where I will chronicle my Tidy Tuesday endeavors. If you are more interested in in the event you can visit the Tidy Tuesday GitHub page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>